Use Embedly to add rich media to your sites and apps. After integrating Embedly, use analytics to understand and grow your audience.

Privacy Policy
==============

Please note that by using pro.embed.ly, api.embed.ly, and related websites (the “Site”) or the services (the “Services”) provided by A Medium Corporation (“Medium”, “we” or “us”), you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site or Services.

**What is the purpose of this Privacy Policy?**

This Privacy Policy discloses our personal information gathering and dissemination practices with respect to the Site and Services.

We have also created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. We recognize that when you provide us with information about yourself that you trust us to act in a responsible manner with that information, and we’re committed to making sure we earn that trust.

**Consent**

By using the Service or submitting personal information through the Service, you expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information according to this Privacy Policy.

We process the personal information we obtain on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information on a server outside your own country. Laws regarding processing personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates"), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your personal information with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

In the event Medium goes through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets to which this Privacy Policy relates, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur.

**What information do we collect from users and how is it used?**

The following describes the types of personal and other information we may collect about you, and how we use and maintain that information:

Information collected online can generally be categorized as either non-personal information or personally identifiable information. Non-personal information is information that cannot by itself be traced back to a specific individual. For example, we know how many calls or queries we receive each day but we do not know the names and email addresses of the persons submitting the queries. Personally identifiable information is information you provide to us that is uniquely associated with you, such as your name or email address.

We do not associate any non-personal information we collect from you, including your search queries and IP address, with the personally identifiable information that you may submit to us. For this reason, we do not consider your IP address to be personally identifiable information.

Registration

Before you can utilize certain Services that we offer on the Site or otherwise, we may ask that you register with Embedly and provide us with your email address, a password, your first and last name and other contact information and personal details. We request this information for identification purposes, to communicate with you regarding your account, and to facilitate the functioning of certain Services. We may keep this information indefinitely, unless you request for account deletion.

Correspondence

If you correspond with us via email, we may gather in a file specific to you the information that you submit. We may keep this information indefinitely unless you request for account deletion.

URL and IP address

Like many other services, Medium collects information about users’ utilization and navigation of our Site and use of Services. This information helps us to design our Site and Services to better suit our users’ needs. For example, our Site or Services will track the URL that you visited before you came to our Site or used our Services, the URL to which you next go, your Internet Protocol (IP) address and any URLs to which you link using the Services. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Site or Services. Your IP address also is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.

Information Collected With Cookies

Like most major websites and services, we may use cookies on certain pages of our Site or pages using our Services. Cookies make using the Internet easier by, among other things, saving your preferences for you. For example, a cookie lets a Site or Services remember that you’ve registered, which allows us to speed up your future activities at our Site or Services, and which allows you to enter your registration information less frequently while visiting our Site or using our Services. We may also use cookies to deliver content tailored to your interests. Our cookies may enable us to relate your use of our Site or Services to personally identifying information that you previously submitted, such as calling you by name when you return to our Site or use our Services. If your browser is set to reject cookies, or if your browser notifies you that you are about to receive a cookie and you reject it, then your use of the Site or Services may not be as efficient or as enjoyable as it would be if the cookie were enabled. The information that we collect with cookies allows us to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze Site or Services usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our Site’s or Services’ content, or sslayout. However, we only use information collected with cookies on an aggregated basis without the use of any information that personally identifies you. You may opt out of our use of cookies by [configuring your browser to reject them](http://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions.shtml).

**To whom does Medium disclose information about you that we collect?**

Medium will not share, rent, sell or otherwise disclose any of the personally identifiable information that we collect about you, except when we have your permission or in any of the following situations:

* We may disclose information that we collect about you to our third-party contractors who perform services for us in order to provide certain services or to complete or confirm a transaction that you conduct with us.
    
* We may disclose information about you as part of a merger, acquisition or other sale or transfer of its assets or business. We do not guarantee that any entity receiving such information in connection with one of these transactions will comply with all terms of this Privacy Policy.
    
* We may be legally obligated to preserve or disclose information about you to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances, such as in connection with illegal activity on our Site or Services or to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal process. Medium reserves the right to preserve or disclose information that we collect to law enforcement or other government officials, as we, in our sole and absolute discretion, deem necessary or appropriate.

If you use our Site or Services outside of the United States, information that we collect about you will be transferred to servers inside the United States and maintained indefinitely (unless you have requested for account deletion), which may involve the transfer of information out of countries located in the European Economic Area. By allowing Medium to collect information about you, you consent to such transfer and processing of your data.

**What security measures does the Site employ?**

To help protect the privacy of data you transmit through this Site or Service, where personally identifiable information is requested, Medium uses technology designed to encrypt the information that you input before it is sent to us. In addition, Medium takes steps to protect the user data we collect against unauthorized access. However, you should keep in mind that this Site and our Services are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond our control.

Medium takes commercially reasonable security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information that you share and that we store.

We restrict access to personal information only to Medium employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. However, no security system can be fully secured; accordingly, Medium cannot guarantee the security of any information you provide to us in connection with the delivery of our Services.

Please also be aware that despite our best intentions and the guidelines outlined in this Privacy Policy, no data transmission over the Internet or encryption method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

**How can you correct or update information that we collect about you?**

You may correct or update information collected about you by managing your account profile or by contacting us at the email or mailing address noted below. We will use reasonable efforts to update our records. For our records, we may retain original and updated information for reasons such as technical constraints, dispute resolution, troubleshooting and agreement enforcement.

**What are the policies of linked sites and other third parties?**

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. You should be aware that when you are on the Site or using the Services, you can be directed to other websites that are beyond our control, and Medium is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties or the content of linked websites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any website. Specifically, if you use Embedly to embed YouTube Videos, you agree that the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy) will apply.

**How will I know about changes in the Privacy Policy?**

Medium reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please visit this page periodically so that you will be apprised of any changes.

**What is our policy on children users of our Site?**

We do not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from persons under 13 years old, and no part of our Site is directed to persons under 13. IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS OUR SITE AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER. If Medium learns that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13 years old has been collected without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained an Embedly account, then you may alert us at the address below and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems.

**Will my employer have access to information that we collect about you?**

If you access our Site or Services as a representative of a third party, such as your employer, that party may review and modify your personal information, ask us to delete your personal information, or request that we cease collecting your personal information. If such a third party asks us to delete your personal information or cease collecting your personal information, we may terminate your right to access our Site or Services.

**How to contact us?**

We are committed to answering inquiries about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. If you have an inquiry or complaint regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at privacy@embed.ly.

Data Protection Statement for European Union Users
==================================================

**Description of Processing Activity**

Embedly collects and stores minimal non-identifying statistical usage data where essential to provide third-party embedded content as a service.

Embedly collects personal or business data related to billing information from its customers.

**Purposes of Processing**

* Provide, test, promote, and improve the services
* Gather usage statistics of services
* Provide third-party embeds
* Process client billing

**Legal Basis**

In order to provide the services, Embedly collects and stores personal billing data about its customers on the legal basis of consent when they create an account and agree to this Privacy Policy.

Embedly also pursues its legitimate interests by collecting minimal non-identifying statistical usage data to provide the services.

**Categories of Personal Data Collected**

People who interact with a third-party embed on a client site:

* IP address
* Browser Information

Customers:

* Name
* Email address
* Password
* Billing information & history

**Categories of Recipients**

Medium shares minimal personal data with third-party processors in order to provide the Services. These processors offer at least the same level of data protection as that set out in this statement. This includes the following categories of recipients:

* Hosting, Storage, & Other Infrastructure
* Security
* Analytics
* Communication & Support
* Payment Processors

**Third-party embedded content**

Embedly facilitates embedding third-party content into customers’ websites. Third-party embeds may in some cases collect personal data and cause it to be stored. The use of personal data by embedded content providers is not covered by this statement, but by the privacy policies of those third-party services.

**Potential consequences of processing**

Embedly collects and stores minimal non-identifying statistical usage data. Individual persons cannot be identified from this data.

**Cross-border transfers**

Embedly is hosted in the United States. By using Embedly services, you authorize us to transfer, store, and use your information in the United States and any other country where we operate. Where data is disclosed to our processors, it is subject by contract to at least the same level of data protection as that set out in this statement.

**Retention**

Embedly and certain of its processors retain browser information (user agent) and IP addresses for two weeks after time of interaction with a particular embed.

Embedly retains client data for the lifetime of your account. If you would like to delete your client information, you may delete your account.

**Rights of data subjects**

1. If you sign up for an Embedly client account, you may at any time correct your personal or billing information from the Manage page.
2. You can also delete your account from the Manage page.
3. You can contact us with questions or complaints through [Embedly support](https://support.embed.ly/hc/en-us/requests/new).
4. You may at any time lodge a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data by Embedly with the Supervisory Authority of your EU member state.

As Embedly does not collect or store personal data other than that related to client accounts, the above are not applicable for people who interact with a third-party embed on a client site.

Consumer Privacy for California Users
=====================================

If you are a California resident, the processing of certain personal data about you may be subject to the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and other applicable California state privacy laws. Beginning January 1, 2020, the CCPA gives you certain rights with respect to the processing of your personal data (known as “personal information,” as described in the CCPA).

This section provides additional privacy disclosures and informs you of key additional rights as a California resident:

Right to Know Request - Under the CCPA, you have a right to request information about our collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information over the prior 12 months, and ask that we provide you with the following information:

1. Categories of and specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.
2. Categories of sources from which we collect personal information.
3. Purposes for collecting, using, or selling personal information.
4. Categories of third parties with which we share personal information.
5. Categories of personal information disclosed about you for a business purpose.
6. If applicable, categories of personal information sold about you and the categories of third parties to which the personal information was sold, by category or categories of personal information for each third party to which the personal information was sold.

To make a verifiable request for information about the personal information we have collected about you, please contact our [support team](https://support.embed.ly/hc/en-us)

Right to Delete Request - Under the CCPA, you also have a right to request that we delete personal information, subject to certain exceptions. You may exercise your right to delete if you have a Embedly account by contacting our [support team](https://support.embed.ly/hc/en-us)

Household Requests - We do not knowingly collect household data. If all the members of a household makes a Right to Know or Right to Delete request, we will respond as if the requests are individual requests.

General Requests under CCPA - if you do not have a Embedly account, we will not have enough information about you to verify your Right to Know and Right to Delete requests since we do not keep sufficient information to reidentify and link you to a prior visit to Medium. You may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information twice per 12-month period. We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your rights under the CCPA.

Requests made through Agents - You may designate, in writing or through a power of attorney document, an authorized agent to make requests on your behalf to exercise your rights. Before accepting such a request from an agent, we will require that the agent provide proof you have authorized them to act on your behalf, and we may need you to verify your identity directly with us.

**Disclosures of Personal Information for a Business Purpose**

In the last 12 months, Embedly has disclosed certain data from the following categories of personal information to the categories of recipients listed above in the 'Categories of Recipients' for one or more business purposes:

Logged in customers:

* Email address (non-public)
* Name (non-public)
* User ID
* Usage history
* Billing information and history

No Sale of Personal Information - Under the CCPA, a “sale” means providing to a third party personal information for valuable consideration. Since Medium doesn’t make money from ads, we don’t collect data to facilitate nor enable third parties to advertise to you. At this time and pending final regulations and guidance interpreting the CCPA, we don't believe any of our data practices constitute a "sale" under the CCPA.

**Contact Information**

A Medium Corporation

799 Market Street, 5th floor

San Francisco, CA 94103, United States of America

**Representative**

Head of Legal - legal@medium.com

_Last Updated:02/24/2020_

#### Product

#### [Documentation](https://embed.ly/docs)

#### [Company](https://embed.ly/company)

© 2024 All Rights Reserved

Connect With Us! [Twitter](http://twitter.com/embedly) [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/embedly) [GitHub](http://www.github.com/embedly)
